Guide to the New York City COVID-19 Web Activism Collection TAM.798
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Peoples Bail Out NYC Twitter, May 2023-ongoing; COVID Bail Out NYC (Box Electronic Records)
  Peoples Bail Out NYC, formerly COVID Bail Out NYC, centralizes funding to post bail, provide support to public defenders, and providing post-release support. Through the website, individuals can donate funding and volunteer to post bail. It also calls for trained social workers, mediators, healers, and individuals trained in conflict resolution to volunteer time to support individuals upon their release from prison or jail. The Twitter feed contains news from the organization related to New York City jails and mass incarceration.
- In the Wake of the Plague: Eros and Mourning, July 2023; Dartmouth University (Box Electronic Records)
  Conference proceedings for the four day symposium on the "converging crises of COVID, racial violence, resurgent nationalism, and environmental collapse" at Dartmouth University. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- We Need a COVID-19 Response that Put People before Profit Petition, May 2020-February 2022; Democratic Socialists of America (Box Electronic Records)
  Petition linked from the New York City COVID-19 action campaign list. Petition on Medicare for All, worker protection, safe housing, and debt forgiveness.
- We Need a People's Bailout for New York! Petition, May 2020-February 2022; Democratic Socialists of America (Box Electronic Records)
  Petition linked from the New York City COVID-19 action campaign list. Petition on making COVID-19 testing and treatment free, protecting Medicaid, keeping workers safe and secure, and other issues.
- The Healing Memorial, July 2023; Detroit Riverfront Conservancy (Box Electronic Records)
  The Healing Memorial was a collaborative project of the City of Detroit Office of Arts, Culture and Entrepreneurship, the Detroit Riverfront Conservancy and the Cranbrook Art Museum where residents were encouraged to create small memorial pouches (fits in the palm of the hand) using fabric from their loved ones or donated material. These fabric pouches were gathered by the thousands to create a tapestry of memories and displayed at Detroit's Huntington Place downtown. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Dollar Bail Brigade Volunteer Guide, May 2020-February 2022; Dollar Bail Brigade (Box Electronic Records)
  Guide linked from the Free Them All for Public Health website on how to bail out people in New York City jails.
- Building Power & Safety Through Solidarity, May 2020-July 2021; DRUM (Organization) (Box Electronic Records)
  DRUM - Desis Rising Up and Moving is a multigenerational, membership led organization of low-wage South Asian and Indo-Caribbean immigrant workers and youth in New York City. Founded in 2000, DRUM's membership of over 3,000 adults, youth, and families is multigenerational and represents the diaspora of the South Asian communities – Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Bhutan, Guyana, India, Nepal, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Suriname, Trinidad & Tobago, and beyond. In over a decade, they have built a model of South Asian and Indo-Caribbean undocumented workers, women, and youth led organizing for rights and justice from the local to the global. Their long-term vision is to build the power of immigrant workers in the U.S in unity with all workers and communities for human rights. They see movements for justice in the U.S. as rooted in working in solidarity with people of the Global South for just global trade, economic, and foreign policies. Their Power and Safety website includes community resources, a community-organizing toolkit, community mutual aid funds, and testimonials documenting community members' experiences during COVID-19.
- #FTA4PH Partner Org Resource Survey, May 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google form surveying for resources in the Free Them All for Public Health community.
- #FTA4PH Phone Bank Resource Survey, May 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google form for a phone bank resource survey in the Free Them All for Public Health community.
- Abolish NYPD-Close Rikers Graphics, July 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Graphics on calls for abolishing the New York Police Department and closing the Rikers Island jail.
- Abolitionist Recommendations to Defund NYPD, with No New Jails by Closing Rikers Now, July 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Pamphlet calling to abolish the New York Police Department and the closing of the Rikers Island jail by rellocating the budget for the 2021 fiscal year.
- Budget Release Talking Points, July 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document containing example tweets related to the defunding the police and closing the Rikers Island jail.
- Free People from Jail, May 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document calling for the release of incarcerated people from New York City jails.
- Free Them All for Public Health, May 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  Free them All for Public Health, or #freethemall4publichealth, is a campaign that demands the release of incarcerated people. The campaign recognizes a longer-term goal of abolition; however, it calls for immediate reductions of prosecution, probation, and court monitoring; the release of people from jails; and the release of people from prisons as measures of reducing the spread of COVID-19. The campaign calls upon individuals to participate in "zaps," actions in which elected officials, and individuals associated with the Department of Corrections, are contacted en masse through phone calls, faxes, emails, and social media. This website documents not only the demands of Free Them All, but the demands of incarcerated people at three city jails. It also lists actions, provides resources on decarceration and abolition, and links to recent news related to COVID-19 and incarceration. #freethemall4publichealth is a parallel campaign with #CloseRikersNOW.
- Free Them All 4 Public Health Virtual Phone Banking Training Document, May 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document on training for virtual phone banking to free incarcerated people from jails.
- PUBLIC FTA4PH Outreach Toolkit, May 2020-July 2021; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Outreach toolkit for the Free Them All for Public Health campaign.
- Reduce Criminalization, May 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document on decreasing criminalization in New York State.
- Response to New York City's 2020 Budget, June 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document on Free Them All for Public Health's response to the 2020 New York City budget.
- Sample Script for COVID-19 Phone Banking, May 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document containing a sample script for COVID-19 phone banking for the release of incarcerated people.
- Tips for Phone Banking, May 2020-February 2022; Free Them All for Public Health (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document for tips for phone banking for the release of incarcerated people.
- Freelance Solidarity Project – Emergency Resource Guide, May 2020-February 2022; Freelance Solidarity Project (Box Electronic Records)
  Resource list linked from the New York City COVID-19 action campaign list. Organized by New York City neighborhood.
- The Museum as Mangrove: How Brigada Puerta de Tierra is Fighting the Gentrification of San Juan, July 2023; Frieze Art Fair (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Carina del Valle Schorske in Frieze on the Storefront for Art and Architecture, a pop-up Puerto Rican museum. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- #FundExcludedWorkers, November 2021-ongoing; Fund Excluded Workers Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  The Fund Excluded Workers (FEW) Coalition is a coalition of labor and activist groups demanding covid relief funding for undocumented workers and those who have recently been released from incarceration, both of whom are being excluded from relief packages. Their campaign calls for the creation of an Excluded Worker Fund, develop through a tax on the wealthy, to "provide direct income support, equivalent to unemployment benefits." On March 16th, 2021, members of the coalition began a hunger strike demanding that legislators in Albany fund excluded workers, which led to a $2.1 billion Excluded Workers Fund. In March 2022, the coalition marched to Albany to promote their platform that called for $3 billion to replenish the Exclude Workers Fund, street vendor legalization, health coverage for all, fair wages, and worker protections.
- #FundExcludedWorkers Coalition Linktree, March 2023-ongoing; Fund Excluded Workers Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  Fact sheets, petitions, and action alerts related to the Unemployment Bridge Program promoted by the #FundExcludedWorkers Coalition.
- #FundExcludedWorkers Hunger Strike, December 2021-February 2022; Fund Excluded Workers Coalition (Box Electronic Records)
  In March-April 2021, excluded workers went on a 23-day hunger strike to demand that legislators in Albany fund excluded workers. On April, the strike ended when the Excluded Workers Fund was passed. This website consists of a playlists of videos from the strike.
- Giving shape to grief: COVID-19 memorials from around the world, July 2023; Globe Newspaper Co. (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Heather Hopp-Bruce in the Boston Globe. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Mask Making Zine, June 2020-February 2022; Gonzalez, Yessica (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page and contains directions on how to make a mask.
- COVID-NYC Documentary Project, July 2023; Gotham Center for New York City History (Box Electronic Records)
  The COVID-NYC Documentary Project at the Gotham Center for New York City History is a clearinghouse for the various efforts by museums, universities, libraries, neighborhood groups, and individuals to historically document New York City's experience with the COVID-19 pandemic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- COVID-19 Community Care Guide, June 2020-February 2022; Herbalista (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page. Practical resources and protocols for community herbalists related to COVID-19.
- Eviction Free NY, May 2021-ongoing; Housing Justice for All (Box Electronic Records)
  Tool created by Right to Counsel NYC Coalition, Housing Justice for All, and JustFix.nyc to assist New York tenants facing hardship due to COVID-19 health risks or lost income to protect from eviction.
- Housing Justice for All, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  Housing Justice for All is a campaign initiated by Upstate/Downstate Housing Alliance. The Alliance is a coalition that seeks to end evictions, end homelessness, and fights for stronger tenant protections. The website contains reports related to rent striking, renters rights, homelessness, and housing unaffordability. The website contains news related to their work on housing insecurity exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Housing Justice For All -- COVID-19 Response, Petition, and Pledge, May 2020-April 2021; Housing Justice for All (Box Electronic Records)
  Housing Justice for All is a campaign initiated by Upstate/Downstate Housing Alliance. The Alliance is a coalition that seeks to end evictions, end homelessness, and fights for stronger tenant protections. The Housing Justice for All website includes links to tenants rights information, links to a bilingual rent strike toolkit (Spanish and English), a map of tenant stories from across the state of New York, a petition, and pledge to join the May 1st rent strike. The Reclaim Our Homes petition is a call to suspend rent and mortgages in New York during the COVID-19 crisis.The petition is sponsored by the Upstate/Downstate Housing Alliance along with twenty-six co-sponsored from various social justice, activist, and housing justice organizations across the New York City and the state of New York. The petition is bilingual (Spanish and English) and links to a Google doc version of the petition that is translated into Chinese. The pledge is translated into four languages including Bangla, Korean, Chinese, and English, and it seeks to build a mass movement of rent strikers beginning in May. It aims to have 6,400 individuals join the pledge.
- Housing Justice For All Twitter, May 2020-ongoing; Housing Justice for All (Box Electronic Records)
  Housing Justice for All is a campaign initiated by Upstate/Downstate Housing Alliance. The Alliance is a coalition that seeks to end evictions, end homelessness, and fights for stronger tenant protections. On March 11, 2020, the Housing Justice for All Twitter feed focuses on housing justice responses to COVID-19 including calls for moratorium on evictions and suspensions of rents and mortgages. The feed includes use of the #CancelRent, #CantPayMay, #HomelessCantStayHome, #ReclaimOurHomes, and #RentStrike hashtag campaigns, and is inclusive of testimonies from tenants across New York as they navigate housing inequality across the state.
- Right to Remain, April 2022-ongoing; Housing Justice for All (Box Electronic Records)
  Right to Remain is a campaign by Housing is a Human Right to pass the Good Cause Eviction (S3082/A5573) bill, which would allow renters to challenge unconscionable rent increases and stay in their homes.
- Reclaim Our Homes: Rent/Mortgage Suspension Now! Petition, May-February 2022; Housing Justice for All (Box Electronic Records)
  Petition to create permanent housing for homeless New Yorkers.
- Coronavirus NYC Neighborhood Food Resource Guides, May 2020-ongoing; Hunter College. New York City Food Policy Center (Box Electronic Records)
  The Coronavirus NYC Neighborhood Food Resource Guide was developed by the Hunter College New York City Food Policy Center in order to "help community members in need with food resources during this challenging time." The website provides links to neighborhood specific guides for free or reduced-cost food programs, meals for students and seniors, meal delivery programs, and resources for immigrants across 59 neighborhoods in each of the five boroughs of New York City (Bronx, Brooklyn, Queens, Staten Island, and Manhattan).
- In Malibu, a Large Hole Is Being Dug to Contain Your Grief, July 2023; Hyperallergic (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Matt Stromberg in Hyperallergic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Through Art, Texans Memorialize Victims of Uvalde Shooting, July 2023; Hyperallergic (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Elaine Velie in Hyperallergic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Urged by Battery Park City Locals, Work Paused on Essential Workers Monument, July 2023; Hyperallergic (Box Electronic Records)
  Article by Valentina Di Liscia in Hyperallergic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Teamsters Joint Council 16 Facebook, January-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  Teamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. During COVID-19, many Teamsters were designated as "essential workers." In January of 2020, over 1,400 essential workers at Hunts Point Produce Market — the largest wholesale produce market in the country — launched a historic, week-long strike. Facing freezing weather and police brutality, the workers refused to concede their demand of Hunts Point Produce Market to raise hourly wage by $1-per-hour. On January 23rd, workers voted to end their strike after approving a new contract that includes a $1.85 wage increase over three years and ends out-of-pocket payments for family healthcare plans. The Teamsters Joint Council 16 Facebook account provides a visual record of the on-the-ground struggle of the strike.
- Teamsters Joint Council 16 Twitter, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  Teamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. During COVID-19, many Teamsters were designated as "essential workers." In January of 2020, over 1,400 essential workers at Hunts Point Produce Market — the largest wholesale produce market in the country — launched a historic, week-long strike. Facing freezing weather and police brutality, the workers refused to concede their demand of Hunts Point Produce Market to raise hourly wage by $1-per-hour. On January 23rd, workers voted to end their strike after approving a new contract that includes a $1.85 wage increase over three years and ends out-of-pocket payments for family healthcare plans. The Teamsters Joint Council 16 Twitter account documents the on-the-ground struggle of the strike, inclusive of short spotlight interviews, photographs, and videos (inclusive of Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez joining the picket line).
- Teamsters NYC, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  Teamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. During COVID-19, many Teamsters were designated as "essential workers." In January of 2020, over 1,400 essential workers at Hunts Point Produce Market — the largest wholesale produce market in the country — launched a historic, week-long strike. Facing freezing weather and police brutality, the workers refused to concede their demand of Hunts Point Produce Market to raise hourly wage by $1-per-hour. On January 23rd, workers voted to end their strike after approving a new contract that includes a $1.85 wage increase over three years and ends out-of-pocket payments for family healthcare plans. The Teamsters website chronicles this effort in a series of news articles. The strike is further contextualized within the pandemic era through a COVID-19 memorial and a campaign page dedicated to the strike.
- Teamsters NYC COVID-19 Rights, January-March 2021; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
  eamsters Joint Council 16 represents 120,000 workers in Downstate New York and Puerto Rico. Joint Council 16 represents workers in a wide range of industries inclusive of horse carriage drivers, truck drivers, public housing workers, airline staff, newspaper printers, film industry workers, manufacturers, construction workers, grocery workers and others. This page contains information on workers rights during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Teamsters NYC Hunts Point Strike, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
- Teamsters NYC In Memoriam: Teamsters Lost to COVID-19, January 2021-February 2022; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America. Joint Council No. 16 (New York, N.Y.) (Box Electronic Records)
- Captivating views of community health workers, July 2023; Johns Hopkins University (Box Electronic Records)
  Article on LaToya Ruby Frazier photoseries on the work of Johns Hopkins physician-researcher Lisa Cooper, her colleagues, and the community health workers who supported and served Baltimore neighborhoods during the pandemic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Justice Committee COVID Cop Watch, June 2020-ongoing; Justice Committee (Box Electronic Records)
  The Justice Committee (JC) is a grassroots organization dedicated to building a movement against police violence and systemic racism in New York City and empowering low-income Latino/as and other people of color to address these issues. By building solidarity with other anti-racist, immigrant and people of color-led organizations, they seek to contribute to a broad-based movement for social justice. JC also seeks to contribute to a coordinated global movement that will attain this world by building a New York City in which people are not victimized by systemic racism and other forms of oppression and do not suffer or fear killings and abuse at the hands of the NYPD and other forms of law enforcement.
- Black America and Covid, July 2023; Killebrew, Sonja J (Box Electronic Records)
  Podcast documenting the Black American experience during the COVID-19 pandemic. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- COVID-19: Sex Worker Harm Reduction Resources, June 2020-January 2021; Krongelb, Malana (Box Electronic Records)
  Google document linked from the SWOP Brooklyn website's COVID resource page highlighting physical and mental health, online work, and financial resources for sex workers.
- Tre Kwon Twitter, May 2020-ongoing; Kwon, Tre (Box Electronic Records)
  Tre Kwon is a writer and editor for Left Voice. She is a Mount Sinai ICU nurse and a member of NYSNA. Kwon joined other activists and workers in several different actions to demand more PPE and to denounce the conditions faced by frontline workers during the COVID-19 crisis. The mother of a newborn, her work and activism has been covered in mainstream and progressive/left news outlets such as BBC, CBS, Democracy Now, and The Intercept. Her tweets related to the struggles of healthcare workers during COVID-19 begin April 3, 2020 and include still and moving image documents and links to media outlets' reporting of healthcare workers during COVID-19
- La Arena Fuera del Reloj: Memorial a las víctimas de COVID-19, July 2023; Lozano-Hemmer, Rafael (Box Electronic Records)
  A Crack in the Hourglass by Rafael Lozano-Hemmer is a digital exhbition to memorialize people lost to COVID-19. A resource featured on the Zip Code Memory Project website.
- Make The Road: Our COVID Response, May 2020-ongoing; Make the Road (New York) (Box Electronic Records)